### Contact

+1 (480) 463-4423 (Work) davidgilliam.info@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gilliamdavid (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Software Testing Leadership Project Management

### Certifications

HTML Essential Training Learning Jira Software

Programming Foundations: APIs and Web Services

Creating a High Performance Culture Programming Foundations: Software Testing/QA

# **David Gilliam**

Forever in a beta state: Learning, growing, and evolving Greater Phoenix Area

## Summary

A professor in college once told me if you follow your passions you'll end up succeeding more often than not. She later confided in me that I embodied this philosophy better than any student she'd ever had up until that point. I like to think that I still do to this day.

Hi my name is David, a self proclaimed Philomath and lover of all things tech. I diagnose a myriad of complex issues regardless of scale, and resolve them all with a smile on my face. I aim to develop a unique leadership style that encourages free thinking and nurtures growth through complex group problem solving. I accomplish this by applying active listening skills, focusing on soft metrics to drive key results, and take a forward thinking approach when setting up policies and processes. I believe preventing stagnation is crucial in an industry that's constantly adapting and growing day by day.

Previously I led a company of +1000 employees in a metric based management style of productivity and was recognized by my company for these efforts. While studying Game Design in college I took an interest in the backend of how everything was setup. I also found the closest thing to a mentor I ever had. He showed me how to handle incredibly tough situations while maintaining the composure and disposition of a seasoned veteran.

Outside of work, I'm actively involved in the community, assisting in various volunteer programs. I am a lover of nature and can often be found hiking and backpacking when not around computer screens and servers.

## Experience

Extra Card

1 year 5 months

Senior Technical Support Engineer

### March 2022 - Present (9 months)

Los Angeles, California, United States

- I helped create and scale the QA system for our department. This is implemented to help track data flow for troubleshooting, and other various metrics.
- I created a process within my department to streamline learning/onboarding for our new hires. This process included a custom checklist that outlines expectations for new hires within the first 90 days of their employment(i.e. first week, 30 days, 60 days, 90 days, etc). These expectations are setup as tasks, and are carried out by select members.

# Technical Support Engineer July 2021 - March 2022 (9 months)

Los Angeles, California, United States

- Part of my duties include gathering and tracking data and statistics based off our issues. This data is used to implement procedural change/structure wherever applicable to increase productivity within the Support department.
- I currently serve as the escalation point of contact for any/all identity/fraud related issues. This includes creating documentation and accompanying training, for not only future SME's, but for the entire support department.

JFQ Lending, Inc.
Information Technology Support Analyst
August 2020 - July 2021 (1 year)
Scottsdale, Arizona, United States

- I have been recognized several times by not only my direct Manager, but the IT Manager for outstanding performance based on our metrics within our ticketing system, as well as my initiative to take on responsibilities and tasks to help the team.
- I created detailed documentation to automate and streamline processes and procedures, within my own IT team as well as within other departments.
- As an Outlook/Office 365 Administrator, part of my job is to setup accounts for our end users, as well as diagnose any/all mail related issues (i.e. held emails within our Spam filter system, run message traces to confirm failed deliveries, etc).

- In order to both recognize individual accomplishments and create a sense of unity within the team, I created a project management system. This system provided complete visibility into any/all progress made on both personal projects as well as team based projects (Computer imaging, account creation, PC Encryption, etc). This system also included contingencies, in the form of custom alerts getting sent out to designated SME's if any unexpected errors would arise inhibiting overall progress. I also created an interface that would change the progress of the project with real-time updates that the entire team could see.
- I created a process within my department to streamline learning/onboarding for our new hires. This process included a New Hire Checklist that sets our team members up for success within their first 90 days of employment, by providing expectations/training on a weekly basis. It also created a sense of accountability, not only for the New Hires, but for us as well when we're training and shadowing them.

Cognizant
Program Analyst
September 2019 - August 2020 (1 year)
Phoenix, Arizona Area

- I provisioned access to various applications per request from the respective Hiring Manager (this process included adding new users to our AD server, and then provisioning said user(s) the necessary objects and attributes per their role).
- As an Outlook/Office 365 Administrator, part of my job is to setup accounts for our end users, as well as diagnose any/all mail related issues (i.e. held emails within our Spam filter system, run message traces to confirm failed deliveries, etc).
- One of the last projects I worked on was creating a series of training videos for the Access Management team. This included training documentation that went over in greater detail.

Transact Campus Inc
Technical Support Engineer
May 2019 - August 2019 (4 months)
Phoenix, Arizona Area

- In addition to my duties in Client Support, I had to troubleshoot our clients' POS systems in the instances in which they'd fail and adjust my workflow accordingly based on the issue (the issue was either at the hardware level, software level, or related to the credit card terminals that was integrated into our software).
- In addition to POS support, we also offered and fully supported security systems. This included setting up security access for door readers that required mag-stripe (and NFC mobile credential) badge access. Other troubleshooting included assistance with Biometric Scanners, and triggered alarms. It is noteworthy that effective troubleshooting required dozens of hours worth of in-house recreation and familiarization.
- I was personally recognized on a consistent basis by upper management for my detailed documentation.
- In addition to my day-to-day tasks and duties, I assisted our clients after hours and on weekends (we would only ever troubleshoot after hours if a client's system experienced an outage, usually having to do with an database going offline). Part of my job duties included occasional escalation to the Level 2 point of contact, which was usually a Manager or Lead.

#### Blackboard

1 year 5 months

Technical Support Engineer
December 2018 - May 2019 (6 months)

Phoenix, Arizona

- In addition to my duties in Client Support, I had to troubleshoot our clients' POS systems in the instances in which they'd fail and adjust my workflow accordingly based on the issue (the issue was either at the hardware level, software level, or related to the credit card terminals that was integrated into our software).
- In addition to POS support, we also offered and fully supported security systems. This included setting up security access for door readers that required mag-stripe (and NFC mobile credential) badge access. Other troubleshooting included assistance with Biometric Scanners, and triggered alarms. It is noteworthy that effective troubleshooting required tens of hours worth of in-house recreation and familiarization.

• I was personally recognized on a consistent basis by upper management for my detailed documentation.

Client Support Specialist January 2018 - November 2018 (11 months) Phoenix, Arizona

- I was responsible for the ticket distribution, as well as case creation to the entire team of Technical Support Engineers (Level 1, Level 2, Level 3, Leads, etc) on a daily basis.
- In order to increase my productivity, I familiarized myself with every aspect of the product (up to the level before a SME). This helped to decrease the overall time instance of an outage on a client's environment.
- Part of my job duties included the testing, configuration, and shipment of a copy of our custom image for that hosts our POS software. In the rare event of an unforseen/time sensitive issue, I'd ship these out to clients with next-day priority.
- As the focal point in our team for inbound assistance, it was up to me to assist our vast clientele (i.e. hundreds of Colleges, Universities, High Schools, Charters, Learning Institutions, etc). This included quickly assessing each issue and whom was the most fit to handle the workload (was often based upon experience, client relationship, but most importantly the issue in and of itself).
- I would use my System Admin knowledge on a daily basis, sometimes to perform (scheduled) upgrades to a client's environment. This occurred at both the database level as well as on their servers.
- I would assist our clients and their merchant's with various issues regarding with their credit card terminals.

Ipro Tech
Technical Support Engineer
April 2017 - August 2017 (5 months)
Tempe, Arizona, United States

• I supported a myriad of web-based applications that fed all stored information to a client's database. This included support for both SaaS and On-Premise models.

- Part of my job duties included occasionally pulling/manipulating the clients' data in their database. This required (beginner to moderate level) working knowledge of SQL/MySQL.
- In the event of an unforseen issue with no workaround, it was my job to report any/all bugs so that development can properly address this. This was done by first, replicating this issue in-house in a controlled environment, then properly logging the issue, and finally submitting said bug upon approval from a Tier 3 or equivalent role.

### Asurion

Support Specialist

November 2015 - April 2017 (1 year 6 months)

Phoenix

- · Mobile Device based troubleshooting
- Working Knowledge of Mobile OS (Android, iOS, Windows Mobile, BlackBerry)
- Complaint Handling & Conflict Resolution
- Remote Desktop Support
- Hardware Warranty Replacement
- Account Credit Dispute and Consulting

### The Master Thinkers

Web System Administrator

October 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 9 months)

**United States** 

- Project Management
- Web Site & Multimedia Design
- FTP Server
- WebMail Administration
- Dreamweaver/Muse & Photoshop

### The Geek Group

Intern

August 2013 - December 2013 (5 months)

Greater Grand Rapids, Michigan Area

- Video editing/rendering
- Animation and Visual FX Composition
- IVR Chat Service Management and Moderation
- File categorization within shared server to improve workflow

## Education

Ferris State University

Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.), Digital Animation & Game Design  $\cdot$  (2010 - 2013)

Macomb Community College

Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Digital Animation · (2008 - 2010)